Zoom uses cookies on this site to improve performance, for analytics and for personalization. Please see our <u>Cookie Policy</u> for details and information on how to adjust your cookies settings. As a candidate for employment at Zoom, your personal data can be processed as described in our <u>Privacy Policy</u>.

Decline Accept Cookies

Accept Cookies

A Sign In

Home Search for Jobs

2022 Front End Development Engineer (INTERN)

Apply

- Remote (CA) Bay Area
- Full time
- Posted 19 Days Ago
- **■** R5735

As a Front End Software Development Engineer Intern, you will utilize your knowledge of application programming to extend product functionality on Windows, macOS, Linux, iOS and Android. This paid internship is for a duration of approximately 12 weeks during the Summer of 2022. The program offers cutting edge projects, as well as a mix of additional types of learning in areas of leadership and business acumen-- and is packed full of fun! Our goal is to provide our interns with world class managed experiences, so we can ensure happiness occurs every step of the way!

· What you'll be doing:

- Write and push high quality code efficiently to the frontend of our application(s)
- Connect with customers to understand their goals and needs and translate those into solutions our team can deliver.
- Design and implement features to improve our systems.
- Ensure systems are continuously monitored and running efficiently with a consistent, unified experience across products, platforms, and devices.
- · Build solutions in a fast-paced and collaborative environment
- Configure tooling for systems scalability, ensure we have capacity for future growth.
- Collaborate with internal stakeholders across the business to drive the delivery of features, processes and happiness.

· Requirements:

 Currently pursuing an undergrad or graduate degree in Computer Science, HCl, Electrical Engineering or a related STEM field.

- A minimum of one year of coding experience with one of the following languages and frameworks: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Angular, React.is, ¡Query
- Sponsorship for employment visa status is not available for this position. You must be legally authorized to work in the United States.
- Available to complete the full 12-week internship program during Summer 2022, with a time commitment of approximately 40 hours per week.
- o Detail oriented, organized, ethical, responsible, and self-motivated.
- Team player, ability to work effectively in a diverse organization.
- Strong communication skills and a desire for continuous learning.
- o A authentic interest in advancing Zoom's mission, values, and culture.

Please apply to no more than two Zoom Summer Internship roles

Ensuring a diverse and inclusive workplace where we learn from each other is core to Zoom's values. We welcome people of different backgrounds, experiences, abilities and perspectives including qualified applicants with arrest and conviction records as well as any qualified applicants requiring reasonable accommodations in accordance with the law.

We believe that the unique contributions of all Zoomies is the driver of our success. To make sure that our products and culture continue to incorporate everyone's perspectives and experience we never discriminate on the basis of race, religion, national origin, gender identity or expression, sexual orientation, age, or marital, veteran, or disability status.

All your information will be kept confidential according to EEO guidelines.

Explore Zoom:

- Hear from our leadership team
- Browse Awards and Employee Reviews on Comparably
- Visit our Blog
- Zoom with us!
- Find us on social at the links below and on Instagram

Charles Zhang

charleszhangmb@gmail.com ❖ (310) 739-0540 ❖ Los Angeles, CA ❖ czhangy.io

EDUCATION

University of California, Los Angeles

Sep. 2019 – Jun. 2023

B.S., Computer Science

Los Angeles, CA

- 3.92/4.0 GPA
- Organizations: ACM, Upsilon Pi Epsilon, Tau Beta Pi

PROFICIENCIES

- Skills: Front-end frameworks | Web design | Object-oriented programming | Agile methodologies | RESTful APIs | Data structures & algorithms | Leadership | Interpersonal communication
- Languages: JavaScript | HTML/CSS | C++ | Python
- Tools: React.js | Vue | Git | Node/Express | MongoDB | Linux | Unity | Microsoft Office | WordPress

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Amplification Project

May 2021 - Sep. 2021

Front-End Developer

Los Angeles, CA

• Implemented a responsive design of the organization's main website using Vue while coordinating with a backend developer to raise awareness of forced migration through the preservation of related art and activism.

Bruinshack Feb. 2021 – Present

Full-Stack Development Intern

Los Angeles, CA

- Designed and developed a responsive review system using Vue and the Vuex library that facilitates ratings and reviews from approximately 2,000 weekly active users looking for apartments in the Westwood area.
- Led a redesign of multiple static pages and the apartment manager portal in order to improve brand visibility and quality-of-life for the user base.

PROJECTS

BruinByte – (github.com/czhangy/bruinbyte)

Front-End Development

- Created and deployed a full-stack web application using React.js, designed to act as a local food review hub for UCLA students, based on the FERN stack.
- Integrated an authentication system and a dynamic ratings/comments system using Google Firebase.
- Learned various methods for communicating effectively within a team and building team chemistry.

DARS++ - (github.com/czhangy/darsplusplus)

Full-Stack Development

- Developed a full-stack web application using the MEVN stack that allows users to engage in course planning
 and attempts to optimize their upcoming schedule using topological sorting.
- Honed a user-friendly, responsive design on the frontend, while developing a simple RESTful API on the backend to practice database management through MongoDB Atlas.

Splekbot – (https://aaisara12.itch.io/splekbot)

Game Developer

 Led the level design team tasked with modelling 3D assets and levels using Unity ProBuilder to emphasize core gameplay mechanics, operating using Agile methodologies.